

Daniel Newbold

Senior Full Stack Engineer - React/React Native, Angular, Vue, Node, PHP, Python, AWS

Address: 4056 Windsor Ln, Milton, FL 32571

Email: newboldd537@gmail.com

I am a senior full-stack developer with more than 10 years of extensive experience in web application development using multiple languages and frameworks. I am proficient in all stages of application development including requirement analysis, designing, coding, testing, and debugging.

As a Senior Fullstack Developer, I am highly proficient in both front-end and back-end technologies, and I have worked on various projects, ranging from small-scale applications to complex enterprise solutions.

Technical Specifications:

JavaScript, Typescript, PHP, Python, Golang, Ruby, C/C++, Java
React/Next, Angular, Vue/Nuxt, Gatsby, Tailwind CSS, GraphQL, D3, ThreeJS
Node/Express, Python/Django, PHP/Laravel/Symfony, Golang, Ruby on Rails
Wordpress, Webflow, Wix, Joomla, Drupal, Squarespace, Shopify
Swift/SwiftUI, Java/Kotlin, React Native/Flutter/Ionic/Xamarin
Stripe, Paypal, Google, Firebase

My strong technical skills and business experience give me the ability to communicate with and create alignment between developers, product owners, stakeholders, and executives.

Please contact me at any time when it is convenient for you to discuss further.

EXPERIENCE

Whitepages

July 2019 - October 2022

Senior FullStack Engineer - Frontend and Backend

- Web application development in .Net based development environment and develop web application components using JavaScript frameworks
- Improved and maintained a core Ruby on Rails web app serving 80k+ page views per minute.
- Work as part of the development team towards the application in an aggressive deadline
- Provide assistance to support engineers and customer service staff in order to resolve production issues as quickly as possible
- Implement systems that are highly available, scalable, and self-healing on the AWS platform
- Experience in testing high-performance, highly-available and scalable distributed systems
- Migrated the system to a microservice architecture.
- Migrated the system to Kubernetes on AWS and helped build tooling to automate deployments using Helm and Jenkins.

Contix April 2015 - April 2018

Senior FullStack Engineer

- Initiated, constructed, and launched two web applications from inception to release.
- Directed the deployment process and engineered resilient serverless technologies to ensure high availability.
- Conducted rigorous testing of customer-facing prototypes pre-deployment, achieving a 99% success rate.
- Optimized web page performance, doubling speed for enhanced user experience and accessibility.
- Ensured website compatibility across 99% of browsers, fostering seamless user interactions.
- Boosted mobile traffic by 20% through the implementation of a mobile-first responsive design strategy.

EDUCATION

Florida Atlantic University

Master of Computer Applications (MCA)

July 2006 - November 2010

SKILLS

- * DevOps/Solution Architect with 8+ years of experience in administration, automation, and systems monitoring
- * Capacity planning and systems monitoring;
- * Excellent knowledge of systems programming, shell (bash) usage, Linux/UNIX commands;
- * Performance tuning, benchmarking, troubleshooting, debugging and systems scaling skills;
- * Ability to use a wide variety of open source technologies and tools;
- * Ability to code and script in Python, Perl, Ruby and Golang;